“Cookies store small pieces of data on the client side, usually identifiers or preferences.
Sessions store user-specific data on the server side, tied to a cookie-based session ID.
Together, they enable persistent login and personalized interactions between client and server.”

app.use(express.json());
app.use(express.urlencoded({extended : true}));

so basically when we send data from frontend to backend, everything is somewhat in a mixed up state, it's not exactly a blob data but we could call that it resembles hexadecimal form of data, which cannot be understood in the backend, and that is when the above two lines helps backend receive the correct data instead of mixed up data. 

“When data is sent from the frontend to the backend, it comes as a raw stream that Express doesn’t automatically understand. The middlewares express.json() and express.urlencoded() act as parsers — they convert that incoming raw request data into a readable JavaScript object and attach it to req.body.
express.json() handles JSON payloads, while express.urlencoded() handles data from traditional HTML forms. Without these middlewares, the backend wouldn’t be able to directly access or interpret the request body.”